http://basc.org.uk/basc-privacy-policy/

BASC Privacy Policy
Privacy Notice – MembershipThe British Association for Shooting and ConservationAbout this documentThis Privacy Notice will help you understand how we collect, use and protect your personal information. You should also show this notice to anyone who may be included in your membership package, for example if you hold a joint or family membership. If you have any queries about this Privacy Notice or how we process your personal information, please contact the Data Protection Officer by email: dpo@basc.org.uk or by post: Data Protection Officer, BASC, Marford Mill, Rossett, Wrexham, LL12 0HL.Who we areThe organisation responsible for the processing of your personal information is The British Association for Shooting and Conservation (BASC) of Marford Mill, Rossett, Wrexham, LL12 0HL. This means that we are a ‘data controller’ under the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) and the Data Protection Act 2018. Our registration number with the Information Commissioner’s Office is Z5528828.What information we collect about youThe personal data you have provided, we have collected from you:name, address and address history, date of birth and gender.contact details including telephone numbers and email address.financial information including bank details and credit/debit card details (although we do not retain complete payment card information).details about your family and dependents.information about your living circumstances (e.g. receipt of any government benefits).identifiers assigned to your computer or other devices including your Internet Protocol (IP) address.criminal convictions, health details and medical history.attendance of events and training courses.How we collect information about youThe personal information we hold about you is that which we collect directly from you, for example:when you apply for membership.when you renew your membership.when you purchase our products or services.when you register to receive information from us.each time you interact with us, respond to communications or surveys, or enter competitions.when you make enquiries or raise concerns with any of our teams.What we use your information for and the legal bases for processingWe may store and use your personal information for the purposes of:administering your membership and shareholder rights contained within the association’s constitution (as is necessary for performance of a contract between you and us and/or as is necessary for our legitimate interests);providing you with insurance cover and related services (as is necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us and/or as is necessary for our legitimate interests);using your payment details to process payments relating to your membership including fees, premiums, renewals of membership and refunds (as is necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us and/or as is necessary for our legitimate interests);sending you information about how to renew your membership (as is necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us and/or as is necessary for our legitimate interests);communicating with you about your membership, policies, and claims, including responding to your enquiries (as is necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us and/or as is necessary for our legitimate interests);undertaking market research and statistical analysis including analysing your use of our website. This allows us to develop new, or improve existing, products and services (as is necessary for our legitimate interests);fulfilling our obligations owed to a relevant regulator, tax authority or revenue service (as is necessary for compliance with our legal obligations and/or as is necessary for our legitimate interests).Our “legitimate interests” as referred to above (and below) include our legitimate business purposes, upholding the roles and objectives of the association contained in the constitution and commercial interests in operating our business in a customer-focused, efficient and sustainable manner, in accordance with all applicable legal and regulatory requirements.Using your personal data for promoting and protecting shootingWe will communicate to you on matters relating to shooting or conservation which we feel are of importance or are detrimental to shooting or conservation by email, SMS and social media.We consider this to be our duty in upholding the roles and objectives in line with the constitution that all members are bound when becoming a member of the association.You can object to receiving these communications at any time. By following the unsubscribe link in our emails or SMS; by sending us your name, address and date of birth via email to dpo@basc.org.uk or by post to: Data Protection Officer, BASC, Marford Mill, Rossett, Wrexham, LL12 0HL.Who we share your data withWhere relevant given the nature of the products and services provided to you, we may also share your information with the following categories of third parties:third party service providers who we instruct for the purposes of handling insurance claims including the claims team, solicitors, medical agencies and police (explicit consent you have given us to act on your behalf);third party service providers who support the operation of our business, such as IT and financial service providers, mailing house (as is necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us and/or as is necessary for our legitimate interests);regulators and law enforcement agencies, including the police, the Financial Conduct Authority, HM Revenue and Customs or any other relevant authority who may have jurisdiction (as is necessary for compliance with our legal obligations).Processing outside of the European Economic Area (EEA)The personal information that we collect from you may be transferred to and processed in a destination outside of the EEA. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for one of our suppliers. In these circumstances, your personal information will only be transferred on one of the following bases:the country that we send the data to is approved by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of protection for personal information; the recipient has agreed with us standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission, obliging the recipient to safeguard the personal information (in particular, our transfer of personal information to suppliers in India and the United States for IT development and IT testing purposes are protected in each case by the use of appropriate model clauses); there exists another situation where the transfer is permitted under applicable data protection legislation (for example, where a third party recipient of personal data in the United States has registered for the EU-US Privacy Shield).To find out more about how your personal information is protected when it is transferred outside the EEA (and if you wish to obtain a copy of the appropriate and suitable safeguards), please contact our Data Protection Officer using the details above.How long your information is keptWe will retain your personal information for a number of purposes, as necessary to allow us to carry out our business. Your information will be kept for up to 7 years on our main systems after which time it will be archived, deleted or anonymised. Some of the archived information may be retained for up to 50 years for the purposes of processing of your existing or future claims. Any retention of personal data will be done in compliance with legal and regulatory obligations and with industry standards. These data retention periods are subject to change without further notice as a result of changes to associated law or regulations. If you have any questions in relation to the retention of your personal data, please contact our Data Protection Officer using the details provided above.Your rightsUnder the GDPR and the Data Protection Act 2018 you have the following rights:to obtain access to, and copies of, the personal information that we hold about you.to require that we stop processing your personal information when you tell us.to require us to correct the personal information we hold about you if it is incorrect.to require us to erase your personal information.to require us to restrict processing in accordance with your instructions.to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit your data to another controller.Please note that these rights may be limited by data protection legislation and we may be entitled to refuse requests where exemptions apply.Where we use consent as our legal basis for processing your personal information, you are entitled to withdraw that consent at any time.If you are not satisfied with how we are processing your personal information, you can make a complaint to the Information Commissioner.You can find out more about your rights under data protection legislation from the Information Commissioner’s Office website: www.ico.org.uk.Do we use ‘cookies’?Yes we do click here to learn more.
Taste of Game
GoShooting
Young Shots
Trade Directory
Ladies Shooting
BASC Films
Menu
Taste of Game
Subscribe to our newsletter
© 2020 BASC – British Association for Shooting and ConservationRegistered Office: Marford Mill, Rossett, Wrexham, LL12 0HL – Registered Society No: 28488RBASC is a trading name of British Association for Shooting and Conservation which is authorised and regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) under firm reference number 311937. You may check this on the Financial Services Register by visiting the FCA’s website or by contacting the FCA on 0800 111 6768.If you have any questions or complaints about your BASC membership insurance cover please email.More information about resolving complaints can be found on the FCA website or on the EU ODR platform.Contact Us – BASC Cookie and Privacy Policy – Terms & ConditionsVisitors are advised that BASC cannot accept responsibility for statements made in advertisements on this, or linked external sites.This website is intended for customers based in the UK and is therefore subject to the UK regulatory regime(s).
